Harry Hamlin

Developer

Seattle, WA 541.760.9005

harryhamlin@gmail.com

Profile

Leadership experience as Director of Operations with years of success overseeing the operations and staff of a mid-sized (\$5MM/40 employees) company, managing both day-to-day operations and long-term growth. Previous leadership experience on Mt Everest and in other outdoor industry sectors. Web Development education and experience through University of Washington.

Experience

University of Washington Coding Bootcamp/Web Development Bootcamp

Oct 2022-May 2023

- Attend over 200 hours of lecture teaching the fundamentals of web development.
- Execute a weekly project creating a functional and useable product deployed to the web
- Gain practical familiarity and use of HTML, CSS, JS.
- Practice and deploy using browser-based technologies such as Bootstrap, React, and Jquery.
- Gain a working knowledge of database management using MySQL and MongoDB.
- Gain practical knowledge and practice server-side development and deployment/delivery.
- Utilize sensible and usable API design.

International Mountain Guides/Director of Operations

January 2021-Present

- Oversee daily operations and manage a multi-leveled and diverse staff.
- Consistently meet and exceed goals, oversee growth of 33% in 2021.
- Coordinate hiring, training, performance evaluation, and growth opportunities for a large (40+) staff.
- Implement and develop a pay structure designed to encourage results-oriented work and professional development, resulting in a measurable increase of workplace satisfaction.
- Implement a multi-platform customer registration system, detailed below.
- Lead a team in overhauling our back-end email system leading to a higher degree of security and allowing for the implementation of a CRM system.
- Lead a well-rounded team by facilitating clear and present communication, through quantitative performance feedback and outlining clear expectations of work duties.
- Implement a complex feedback system for staff performance targets.
- Manage an administrative team collecting sensitive information and oversee dissemination to staff.
- Work closely with governmental agencies, physicians, and private industry writing and implementing dynamic Covid-19 policies.
- Work closely with governmental agencies in operating within permit boundaries while still maximizing performance and financial outcomes.
- Create and execute marketing strategy and content based on quantitative feedback.
- Oversee the growth and implementation of retail strategy, including buying.

International Mountain Guides/Senior Supervising Guide, Everest Exped. Team Leader

June 2016-January 2021

- Oversee a small-to-medium-sized staff (2-10) in high-risk scenarios.
- Manage the risk, expectations, and well-being of staff and clientele in hyper objective-based climbing guiding.
- Balance client-facing and staff-facing communication when implementing strategy.
- Assist in high-hazard rescue when required.

Other Leadership Experience

Crystal Mountain Ski Patrol/Shift Supervisor/ June 2014-January 2019

AIARE/Avalanche Education Course Leader/ November 2017-Present

Projects

Cocktail Generator

- Developed a cocktail generator on a 3 person team using Javascript, HTML, and Bulma.
- Managed deployment of code via github

Client Registration System

- Developed and implemented a multi-platform customer registration system, using AirTable, Docusign and Zapier.
- Implemented code executing a live response view for clientele showing live availability.
- Managed team in build and deployment.

Explosives Data Collection System

- Developed and implemented a collaborative system tracking the usage of explosive ordinance across a 30-person team.
- Managed local storage of CSV and Excel file storage on local system.

Education